what lands belong to
какие земли принадлежат
you historical
вам исторические
Which Read history Well what
Какие Почитай историю Ну какие
exactly Donbass
именно Донбасс
Odessa Zaporozhye this is all Our
Одесса Запорожье это всё Наши
Lands that Lenin gave you Ukraine did not exist Let's
Земли которые Ленин подарил вам Украины
talk normally come on
было Давай нормально поговорим давай
How old are you Well it seems to me I'm
Тебе сколько лет Ну мне кажется мне мне
20 normally It seems to me we won't talk
20 нормально Мне кажется мы не поговорим
at all why am I communicating normally Yes
вообще почему я нормально общаюсь Да
because I have ruined my mood now
потому что я сейчас себе настроение
I don't not a
испортила я не не
hundred what happened Yes
соткон что случилось
no In short not with this side I started
Да не Короче не этой стороной начал
sawing But with this side and now I have to
пилить А этой стороной и теперь ноготь
build up my nail again Trouble trouble Where are
наращивать Беда беда
you from nails are
Ты откуда са ногти это
sacred I'm from
святое Я с
Krasnodar What do you
Краснодара Кем
work as a sales consultant I
работаешь продавец-консультант
understood and your whole life depends on this file of yours
понял и от этой твоей пилочки зависит
yes some kind of wavy where is the
да какой-то волнистый где
buff do you have someone you know who is at
бафик у тебя есть кто-то из знакомых кто
war
на войне
now from your acquaintances
сейчас из знакомых
and the ex is considered Yes it is considered Well that is
а бывший считается Да считается Ну то
people you know yes ex yes
есть люди которых ты знаешь да бывший да
And how did he get to the
А как он попал на
war well When we broke up with him he
войну ну Мы когда с ним расстались он он
said that he would prove by this that he
сказал что типа этим докажет что он меня
loves me I was
любит мне было на это
already ready for this and what did he prove
уже и что он доказал
He seemed to prove to me that he
Мне он походу доказал что он
just exactly that and there is
просто вот именно
someone you know who is already
а есть кто-то из знакомых кто уже
wounded
раненый
dead Now
погибший Сейчас
wait I just have Like if anyone
погоди у меня вот только Типа если кого
I know it's only the ex when he went on a
я знаю это только бывший когда пошёл по
contract And how do you think
контракту А как ты вообще считаешь из-за
why this War is
чего эта Война
going on Why is the war going on Well I do
идёт из-за чего война идт Ну из-за чего
n't know why but I know that Well
не знаю но я знаю что ну пер первая
first we started Well I understand Yes how do you
первые начали мы Ну понял да как вообще
feel about this
относишься к этой
war Well I feel terrible I
войне к войне Ну отношусь ужасно вот мне
just feel sorry for the people in Ukraine Especially those who
просто людей на Украине Особенно тех кто
did nothing at all Like our people are just
вообще ничего не сделал типа просто наши
shooting at residential buildings a lot of
стреляют по жилым домам умирает много
people are dying especially children who just
людей особенно детей которые просто
live in the house
проживают в доме
And how do people in Russia feel
а как вот вообще люди в России относятся
about this war Here you are As I understand it you are against the
к этой войне Вот ты Я так понимаю против
war and the
войны а
rest my sister is also against the
остальные у меня сестра тоже против
war
войны у
I have three
меня три
friends who are also against the
знакомых тоже против
war We even just the other day When yesterday was the
войны у нас даже вот на днях Когда вчера
fourteenth Yes yes I have a friend
четырнадцатое было Да да у меня знакомый
in short Vova Well you Okay I won't
короче Вовка ну ты ж Ладно имя не буду
name him he was celebrating something on February 14th Well he
называть у что-то 14 февраля отмечал Ну
got drunk of course
набухался конечно
and made such a statement that he will try With
и предъявил такое что он будет пытаться
all his might to end this
Всеми силами чтобы типа закончить эту
war Well done Oh
войну Молодец
well when they say anything but in
О ну когда на всякое говорят а в
reality it's No he's even sober
реальности это Нет он он даже трезвый
It's  he says this this is already stable with
Это говорит это это это уже стабильно у
him and how do you think who is to blame for this
него а как ты думаешь кто виноват в этой
war
войне
Putin And what are you going out to talk about here
Путин А о чём ты выходишь поговорить тут
in chat
в чат
roulette Yes, I generally came in like in a
рулетке Да я вообще зашла типа в
normal mood But
нормальном настроение Но
here it was
тут его
ruined so you need to come in and
испортили так надо заходить и Россию
choose Russia in order to communicate with Russians for
выбирать чтоб с россиянами
me the Armed Forces are too early about nothing so I don’t
общаться мне ВС рано про ниче не име так
mean that you need to communicate with
вот не имею в виду что нужно общаться с
Russians and talk to them about the fact that we do
россиянами и с ними говорить о том что
n’t need this war That’s exactly what
не надо эту войну Вот именно что мне
Russia ruined my mood I understood And
Россия испортили настроение понял А
how well that’s how it’s
как ну вот так
usually Well these
обычно Ну это
were acquaintances of my ex ex
были знакомые Моего бывшего бывшего
They met me T roulette I
Встретили меня Т рулетке
understood how do you see your future in
понял как видишь своё будущее в
Russia I’m still finishing up and
России я сейчас всё равно дорабатываем
leaving
уезжаю как
anyway do you have any questions for me
бы ко мне есть какие-то
What do you mean you
вопрос Что ты имеешь
asked the question incorrectly how do you
на неправильно задала вопрос как ты
feel about the
относишься к
war negatively of course I think that
войне негативно конечно Я считаю что
Russia attacked Ukraine and should
Россия напала на Украину и должна
withdraw its troops and that’s it Well look Well
забрать свои войска и всё Ну смотри Ну
some Russians are also not
некоторые россияне вот тоже же не
guilty exactly you know some
виноваты именно вот знаешь некоторые
residents who also
жители которые тоже
live Well we understand Look we
проживают Ну мы понимаешь Смотри мы
understand that there are some residents
понимаем что есть некоторые жители
who are not guilty but we don’t know yet
которые не виноваты но мы пока не знаем
which ones exactly  that is, you can't say
какие именно то есть нельзя же сказать
this one is guilty, this one is not guilty. We now
этот виноват этот не виноват Мы сейчас
consider all of you guilty, but when the
считаем всех вас виноватыми а вот когда
war ends, then we'll figure it out.
закончится война тогда будем разбираться
Who was guilty, who wasn't guilty,
Кто был виноват кто не виноват
maybe. Well,
может
God grant that it
Ну дай Бог чтобы она поскорее
ends soon, but you know, it ended on that, you
закончилась но закончилась знаешь на том
know, no one will shoot anyone,
знаешь никто кого раз перестреляют
that's just because what. Well, it's come down to two, that's
вот просто на том что что Ну дошло до
enough seriously fighting, to what two, well,
двоих что ну хватит серьёзно воевать до
like, to Zelensky and to
каких двоих ну типа ну до Зеленского и
ours. So, as for Zelensky,
до нашего Так а что до Зеленского
Zelensky already understands that why
Зеленский и так ну понимает что зачем
war?
война
It wasn't Zelensky who attacked
Это ж не Зеленский напал на
Russia. Well, I
Россию Ну я
know, why come to two. Well, look, in order for
знаю зачем до двоих Ну смотри как бы для
everything to stop when a maniac attacks you, it's not necessary for it to come to
чтобы всё остановилось нужно не чтобы до
two, for it to come to the maniac, for him to
двоих дошло чтобы до маньяка дошло чтобы
stop, because the one who was attacked, if
остановился ведь тот на кого напали если
he stops, he'll be
он остановится его у правда так и тут по
judged here, that is, Ukraine cannot
судим то есть Украина не может
stop. But it's not like we're
остановиться А это же не то что мы себе
there. Oh, let's attack, in short, let's play
там О давай мы нападём короче поиграемся
war, we're defending our homeland, our
в войнушку мы защищаем свою родину свою
territory, seriously. It would be better if this war had
территорию серьёзно Лучше бы эта война
never even started. Well, it's already IT,
даже не начиналась Ну вот она уже ИТ уже
it's already a
идёт это уже
reality. Well, because
реальность Ну потому что
seriously a lot of
серьёзно много погибло
people died the same ones svosh neko the same ones just
людей тех же самых свош неко тех же
residents And you had drones flying to Krasnodar
жителей А у вас в Краснодар прилетали
and
беспилотники да
not just
причём не
one how did people react to
один как люди реагировали на
this well they flew when I was
это ну они прилетали тогда когда меня в
not in Krasnodar yet Well how And where are you
Краснодаре ещё не было Ну как А ты
from I lived in
откуда я сама жила в
Samara And what did you come to Krasnodar And
Самаре А что в Краснодар приехала А у
I had a baa here mnet povi I
меня тут уба была мнет пови я
stayed I
осталась
understood ok I'll run
понял хорошо побегу
on
дальше
ok and it seems that everything so that it would
о'кей и вроде всё на чтобы до обоих
reach both of them to whom to Putin and
дошло до кого до Путина и
Zelensky Hello
Зеленского Здравствуйте
Good evening where are you from such a
Добрый вечер вы откуда такая
beauty Yes it doesn't matter it's important already seeing
красавица Да это неважно важно уже видя
you it doesn't matter And why did I knock
вас то уже неважно А что так я сразил
you down
вас на повал
Of course we found each other with our appearance
Конечно мы своим видом друг друга нашли
You are also
Вы тоже
cute
симпатичные
of course some kind of horror where is the horror where are
конечно ужас какой-то где ужас
you
Вы
from it doesn't matter Look at yourself like that
откуда неважно Посмотрите на себя так
Let's talk normally Where are you from
Давай нормально поговорим Откуда ты
baby it doesn't matter I won't go damn your eyebrows
малышка неважно я не буду го блин брови
Cool you have
Классные у тебя нежные
such gentle ones What are you talking about here
такие О чём тут общаешься
nothing about who is at war your brother husband
не о чём кто у тебя на войне брат муж
son everyone
сын все
someone has already
кто-то уже
died Yes
погиб Да
who doesn't matter Well tell me who is the husband or  son I won't
кто неважно Ну скажи кто муж или сын не
say let's have a normal conversation I'll say well tell me I
скажу давай нормально пообщаемся скажу
communicate normally Look I don't
говори я же нормально общаюсь Смотри я
quarrel
не ссорюсь
who
кто
died my close relative
погиб мой близкий родной человек
husband no
муж нет
boyfriend And how is he and
парень А как он а
who is my friend And how did he end up in the
кто мой друг А как он попал на
war they
войну его
took him away
забрали
when recently They don't take it away from
когда недавно Так у вас же не забирают У
you They only go under contract from you
вас же только по контракту идут
that's why My friend why do they go under contract with
поэтому Друг мой почему по контракту у
us
нас
I'm telling you they don't take you they
идут Я же говорю вас не забирают вас
only go under contract they go
только по контракту идут по контракту
under contract of course he went under contract they
идут конечно то он по контракту пошёл
took him of course they didn't take him but he
забрали конечно не забрали его а он
wanted to
захотел бабки
make some money Well no He wanted to
срубить Ну нет Он хотел родину
protect his homeland And what happened to the homeland our
защитить А что с Родиной случилось
homeland is
родина у нас
wonderful wonderful no What happened that he
прекрасная прекрасная не Что случилось
went to defend it that
что он пошл её защищать что на неё
someone
кто-то
attacked it he went to win back his lands which ones
напал он пошёл отвоевать земли свои
belong to
какие которые принадлежат
us which lands belong to you
нам какие земли принадлежат вам
ka Read history Well which ones
ка Почитай историю Ну какие
exactly Donbass
именно Донбасс
Odessa Zaporozhye this is all Our
Одесса Запорожье это всё Наши
lands which Lenin gave
Земли которые Ленин подарил
you Ukraine was not respected
вам Украины не было почита
now get rid of the sovoks yes Well
сейчас избавляетесь от совков да Ну
look they don't take the gifts back
смотри подарки назад не забирают
Listen to me Give the gifts back no
Послушай меня Давай подарки назад не
take away yes yes yes yes gifts don't take away
забирают да да да да подарки не забирают
of course please get rid of
конечно избавьтесь пожалуйста от
all the houses that you built under
всех домов которые вы построили при
Brezhnev
брежневе
you didn't do anything yourselves you yes We are
при вы ж ничего сами не сделали вы да Мы
cunning we are cunning we rode on your shoulders
хитрые мы хитрые мы на ваших плечах
And what now and what are
выехали И что теперь
you and what do you have And what did we
и что вы и что вы имеете А и что мы
want Yes we deceived you under Brezhnev
захотели Да мы вас обманули при брежневе
adventure you built
приключ вы нам построили
houses for us so please destroy what you
дома так пожалуйста разрушьте то что вы
did why why how is this our
сделали зачем зачем как это это наши
monument monuments you destroy monuments we
памятник памятники разрушаете памятники
want and destroy Yes we deceived you we
хотим и разрушаем Да мы вас обманули
specially put up a monument so that they would
специально поставили памятник чтобы они
build houses and now we are
построили дома а теперь памятники
destroying monuments and that's it and destroying the houses that were
разрушаем да и всё так и дома разру что
built under us Well how did we you that's the point
при нас построили жем Ну как мы ж вас в
we are you all this is a sovok We
том-то и дело мы вас это всё савок Мы
deceived you look We specially put up
обманули смотри Мы специально поставили
monuments to Lenin so that Brezhnev and Khrushchev
памятники Ленину чтоб Брежнев и Хрущёв
would build houses and now we are taking it away and that's it Yeah and
настроил дома а теперь и забираем и всё
what about the houses where you live Why oh
Угу и что дома где вы живёте Зачем о у
nothing you will destroy your Khrushchev houses Well why
ничего хрущёвки свои разрушите Ну зачем
and live in a barn somewhere Live in
и живите в сарае где-нибудь Живите в
your barn  guy how did
сарае твой парень как
my boyfriend die yeah Well this
погиб мой парень да Ну вот этот
friend my boyfriend didn't die And what happened to him
дружок мой парень не погиб А что с ним
my
случилось мой
husband colonel colonel Yes what regiment
муж полковник полковник Да какого полка
straight colonel of the Strategic Missile Forces and this missile man he's
прямо полковник РВСН а это ракетчик он
not at war he's sitting and sitting out I
не на войне он сидит отсиживаться
understand Yes and he's not sitting at war and not
понял Да и он сидит не на войне и не
sitting out he's where he should be Yes no no he's where
отсиживаться он там где он должен быть
he should be and
Дат нет нет он там где он должен быть и
how he's [ __ ] you
как он вас долбит
Ay it seems she
Ай походу онала
herself did it like that
сама так
Hello Hello I remember you you're
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Я вас помню вы
from Sakha settlement
из саха посёлок
Mirny why For what Well that's right from the
Мирный зачем Для чего Ну правильно из
Republic of Sakha settlement Mirny You yes yes I remember
Республики Саха посёлок Мирный Вы да да
you remember you
Я вас помню помню вам
heart Why just like that listen
сердечко Зачем просто так слушайте
Tell me how it happens that
Расскажите вот как так получается что
Sakha is the richest region there is gold
Саха богатейший регион есть золото
diamonds the richest in the world And why do
алмазы самые богатые в мире А почему так
people live so poorly ask everyone
бедно живут люди всех спрашивайте а
please Yes
пожалуйста Да
why is all this It's
почему это всё
always politics Well what politics who
Вот всегда политика Ну что политика кто
takes all your
забирает все ваши
money Moscow And why does Moscow so easily
деньги Москва А почему Москва так просто
take all your money Yakutia and because
забирает все ваши деньги Якутии а потому
they are there in short
что они там короче
corruption and then and
коррупция а потом и
so it was
так это
there Everything is fine I understood Listen
вот там был Всё нормально понял Слушайте
and here's a
а такой
question If Moscow didn't take your
вопрос Если бы Москва не забирала ваши
money You would be rich
деньги Вы бы богато
lived I don't think I will
жили не думаю я
never come this is Russia my
свою никогда не приду это Россия моя
homeland So eat You get Russian
родина Так что еди Ты русская получаешь
or who are you
или кто
Russian then Cool And you are the most
ты русская тогда Прикольно А ты самая
Russian Russian Rus'
русская русская Русь
Yes And what does this have to do with it Well you are Russian mother
Да А причём тут это ну ты русская мама
Russian father Yakut And mother Russian father Yakut
русская папа якут А мама русская папа
And who am I and who am you
якут А ты
Fin You are who I am Fin from Finland Yes go
Фин Ты кто Я Фин из Финляндии Да иди
Toda understood Well tell me who are you Russian
Тода понял Ну расскажи ты кто русская
or
или
Yakut And by dad and by dad I am Circassian
якутка А по па а по папе я черкешенка
then
тогда я
who am I dopa
кто у меня допа
yes Oh dad is half Circassian on And who is
да О папа на половину черкес на А кто
Yakut
якут У
Your dad is half Circassian and
вас папа нал половину черкес и
half Yakut And mom is Russian understood
наполовину якут А мама русская понял
further what understood And your dad And my daughter is
дальше что понял А у твоего па А дочка у
Armenian And your husband is Armenian yes
меня армянка А у тебя муж армянин да
what I just walked around and just an Armenian
какую я просто нагуляла а просто тебе
made you a daughter
армянин сделал дочку
yes yes How old is your daughter now what are
да да Сколько сейчас дочке
you
лет ты что
Pronya Two
Проня Два
grandchildren are a daughter too or does she have a husband
внука дочка тоже или у неё есть муж
they don't communicate with me at all And
они со мной вообще не общаются А
why Because I yes I didn't
почему Потому что я да я не
raise you understood you didn't raise you And
воспитывал понял ты не воспитывала А
why  you didn't
почему ты е не
raise her Well because I gave birth early
воспитывала Ну потому что я рано родила
and I had to, well, life is like that,
и мне надо было вот ну жиз
although I
такая ну хотя я её вот
took her,
вози пошл
you communicate normally, we communicate normally And your
ты нормально нормально общаемся А тебя
wife and, oh, daughter, congratulate you on Mother's Day,
там жена с ой э дочка с Днём матери
they
поздравляет они меня вообще
blocked me a long time ago And do
заблокировали давным давно А мужчина
you have some kind of man now
какой-то у тебя сейчас
And why is it that you have a black eye if you have a black eye That
есть А почему это что
means you have a
фингал раз есть фингал Значит есть
man,
мужчина
yes And I'm
да А я с ним
breaking up with him I left him Why did I leave
расстаюсь я от него ушла почему ушла от
him Because he often does me, he does me, but
него потому что он меня часто он меня а
no, he does me You know,
нет он меня
even my brothers
знаете мои даже братья
know that he chained me up and handcuffed me with a
знают то что он меня вот приковал и
belt, it's brutal I them
ремнём наручниками
Stop my brothers In
жесть я их Останови мои братья
short, I
Короче я их
stopped them You I don't like pushing and
останавливала ты Я не люблю сталкивать а
you were once in prison You were in prison
ты сидела когда-то В тюрьме сидела
Yes, how long did you sit for,
Да сколько
several times, what were you in prison for, what were you in
несколько за что сидела за что сидела В
prison for, I guess And now I'm
тюрьме поди А сейчас я
convicted, now
осуждён сейчас
convicted Yes, I have a suspended sentence,
осуждён Да у меня условка зака
if it weren't for the suspended sentence, they
не если бы за услов не было реальный
wouldn't have given me a real sentence Well,
срок дали бы
somehow it's like that
не Ну как-то так
now 115 111
сейчас 115 111
105 If it was 115, that's it  murder yes or
105 если было 115 это убийство да или
whatever you have there
что там у
105 they wanted to stick it to me and 111 part
105 это мне хотели прилепить а 111 часть
two now I have a suspended sentence I
вторая сейчас у меня условка
understand And what do you
понял А кем
do for a living I am a professional
работаешь никем Я профессиональ об
slacker I am a former
бездельница я бывший
cop And then I worked in security And now
мент А в охране работала потом А сейчас
I don’t work at all I don’t want to work How do you
я вообще не работаю не хочу работать Чем
make money for a living
зарабатываешь деньги на жизнь
[laughter] the
[смех]
money just comes to me
мне просто деньги сами приходят
like I don’t know it
как не знаю
comes and I don’t want it and that’s
приходит а я
why I go to the club in Alcoholics Anonymous
их и поэтому я хожу в клуб в анонимных
to improve
чтобы исправиться
And what is there in the club of Alcoholics Anonymous No there is nothing wrong there
И что там в клубе анонимных
yes they go there not seriously I’m really saying
да проходят там не серьёзно говорю
they
они с
went to you and not to Moscow You would live
шли вам а не в Москву Ты бы жила
Normally of
Нормально
course and who is to blame for the fact that you
конечно а кто виноват в том что так вы
live so
живёте
badly
плохо
ambiguously what is
двояко что
ambiguous what is ambiguous I answered
двояко что двояко я ответила же
ambiguously not in a year
двояко не за о год
who will buy me a phone again
телефон кто мне будет телефон опять
how much do you drink a
покупать сколько пьёшь в
day Don’t switch baby don’t
день не Переключай малышка не
switch 0500 05 a day well normal
Переключай 0500 05 в день ну нормальный
stmp
стмп
Listen what do you think Putin is a good
Слушай а как ты считаешь Путин хороший
president I don’t know and you voted  for
президент не знаю а ты голосовала за
him
него
that the alarm clock the alarm
что будильник
clock broke such a lioness
будильник сорвался такая львица
Hello Hello where are you from I
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте откуда мне
think I've seen you somewhere I'm from Russia
кажется я вас где-то видела Я из России
I'm from
Я из
Belarus I have Ukraine written Well
Беларуси У меня написано Украина Ну это
I put this to communicate with Ukrainians and
я ставлю чтобы с украинцами общаться а
yes yes And what city in Russia are you from
да да А Вы из какого города России
Yekaterinburg my father was from Sverdlov
Екатеринбург у меня отец из Свердлов
born when he was SVS
родом ког был СВС
with in his birth certificate it was
с у него в свидетельстве рождения было
written
написано
Sverdlov It's clear what you
Свердлов Понятно кем
work as I work in education as a
работаете Я в образовании работаю кем
teacher and what do you talk about here at least in
учитель а чём тут общаетесь
fact there are
хоть о чём на самом деле здесь в
basically few people here very much like you have
принципе мало людей очень как там у вас
now from San because we Belarus
сейчас из Сан потому что у нас Белоруси
generally said that in Russia everything is
вобще говорили что в России всё
fine like there is oil gas and
нормально типа там нефть газ и
everything Well oil gas Maybe there is Well yes
всё Ну нефть газ Может есть
yes to sing in general we well
Ну да да поть вообще у
damn as if you
нас ну блин как бы
see we have as if people Well let's say he
видите у нас как бы люди Ну вот допустим
went to McDonald's yes For example here Well
вот ушёл в McDonald's да На пример вот
in principle yes Here they can make cotties cm
Ну в принципе да Вот делать котты см
All well as if what can I also do
могут Все ну как бы что я могу тоже
here people just see the top of
сделать вот просто люди видят верхушку
this that is, they let's say they see this Well a
этого то есть они допустим видят вот что
bun and a bun they don't see another
А ну Булка и булка они не видят другую
as if picture of the world they don't see
как бы картину мира они не видят
let's say McDonald's and they  built a
допустим вот McDonald's а они построили
house, a McDonald's house, or what, if I'm
дом дом Макдак что ли называется если я
not mistaken, that is, a house for
не ошибаюсь а то есть это дом для
sick children who, well,
больных детей которые А ну вот
for example, children with cancer who are
онкобольные например дети которые
being treated for a very long time and they need Well, so
лечится а очень долго и им нужно Ну
that they were with their parents, it
чтобы они были с родителями у нас это
was just, well, at some point,
было просто ну в какой-то момент
impossible for us, so that it would be
невозможно
easier for them to undergo
чтобы им легче было проходить
rehabilitation so that they would not be taken away from their
реабилитацию чтобы они не отнялись от
families in order to undergo
семей для того чтобы проходить
rehabilitation, in fact, they did this, they did
реабилитацию по сути они вот это делали
not build a single house throughout Russia, there
не строили ни один дом по всей России
were many So, accordingly, like, well,
было много Вот соответственно как бы ну
when they ask me like, well, how are the
когда меня спрашивают типа ну вот как
sanctions there Well, like, no, I
там санкции Ну как бы нет не полкам я
miss the shelves, but That's because, like, under the
скучаю а Вот потому что как бы вот по
other system that was, that is, it's
другой системе которая была то есть это
sad, they have a very large company,
грустно у них очень большая компания
charitable
благотворительному
relations, just here you see you see
отношения просто тут видишь вы видите
a little, like, basically, a different
немножко как бы в основном другую как бы
picture, that is, like, well, no beech No, well,
ну картину то есть типа ну нет бука Нет
although it's not only the buns that have left Well, and in
хотя тут не только же булки ушли Ну и
general, somehow It's strange that
вообще как-то Странно что
this is like, here, everything is a little more complicated San,
это как бы тут немножко всё сложнее Сан
they, like, they gave birth to, like, how to
они как бы они породили как бы как
say, there is no competition if there is no
сказать там нет конкуренции если нет
competition, accordingly, everything is with
конкуренции соответственно как бы всё с
ours Well, yes, we can, buns can
наше Ну есть да мы можем булки можем
sew clothes Well, let's say, for example, I
шить одежду Ну допустим вот я по детской
can say about children's clothes, let's say our brands were
одежде могу сказать допустим наши бренды
some good companies Although
были были неплохие какие-то фирмы Хотя
if you look into it, even the fabrics there,
если разобраться то даже там ткани
for example, were most likely not ours But
например были не наши скорее всего Но
they, as if, as soon as the stores left,
они как бы как только ушли магазины там
all sorts of like Makeya, left the market, then earlier,
всякие типа маке с рынка ушли то раньше
let's say, Makeya was, in principle, accessible
допустим макея была в принципе доступ
relatively
относительно
Yes, our some brands that are
Дада наши какие-то бренды которые
decent, are they, in principle, cheaper because they
приличные ли в принципе дешевле потому
won't take, like, when there is, well, well, well, well, really Yes,
не будет брать вот как бы это когда есть
but when they left the
вот ну другое Да но когда ушли как бы с
market, as if, the prices just jumped to the sky, like, well,
рынка цены просто до небес вскочили как
well, really, and therefore And
бы ну прямо вот ну реально и поэтому А
salaries didn't grow, like, well, I don't know
зарплаты не выросли как бы ну я не знаю
how it is with you now, in my opinion, it's
как у вас там сейчас это по-моему у вас
easier for you It's also difficult for us in
полегче У нас тоже тяжело в
Belarus Well, as if
Белоруси Ну вот у нас как бы ещё цены на
housing prices also jumped, as if, well, in general, everything
жильё вскочили как бы ну в общем всё
jumped Do you have any relatives, any
вскочила у вас кто-то из родствен из
relatives, anyone at war
родственников кто-то есть на войне
No, no How do you feel about this in general? A
Нет не А как вообще к этому
provocative
относитесь провокационный
question I don't feel about this I'm a girl,
вопрос я к этому не отношусь Я девочка
thank God, that's why I don't feel about it at all
слава Богу вот поэтому никак не отношусь
How can you feel about
вот как бы как можно относиться к
this I don't even know  And what do you think is the
этому даже не знаю А как вы считаете
reason for this War at all, frankly
из-за чего эта Война идёт вообще да
speaking, no matter what, I
никак не счита чест говоря равно из чего
want it to be a law, I do
ось хочу чтобы она закон
n’t know how much it’s considered there now,
не знаю насколько как бы это сейчас там
well, I’m not
вообще считается ли это ну как бы я не
doing anything there to discredit it or anything
занимаюсь там дискредитации или чем-то
else, I won’t say anything on the topic,
ещё я не буду как бы ничего на тему
well, I want it to be, in
говорить Ну как бы да я хочу чтобы
short, you’re afraid to just talk about
Короче ты боишься просто говорить про
it, I want it to end, but I don’t have any
это Я хочу чтобы она закончилась а
particular desire to figure out why it started, what happened, to be honest, and well,
особого желания нет Если честно и как бы
listen, there is such a thing that many of us are
ну слушай есть такое что да у нас многие
afraid, this is a fact, you too, yes, we have in
боятся это факт У вас ведь тоже да у нас
general, we And before that, everyone was afraid, like, here in
вообще у нас И до сво боялись типа тут в
Belarus,
Беларуси все
Well, yes, like, that’s
Ну да как
why, like,
бы вот поэтому как бы
here, I even thought, by the way, how did it
тут я даже я вот я кстати думал да как
happen that we were in the
так получилось что вот мы были в
Soviet Union, all of us, yes, republics, and we
Советском Союзе все да республики и мы
went our separate ways, the
разошлись каждый пошёл своей дорогой у
Ukrainians somehow managed to make it so
украинцев получилось как-то сделать так
that they choose their own presidents, yes,
что они себе выбирают президентов да у
they have democracy, and here in Belarus, in
них демократия А у нас в белорусси в
Russia, Vaty, this is what
России у вати вот
happened, Listen, well, I don’t know, it seems to me,
получилось Слушай ну не знаю мне кажется
up to a certain point, as far as I know, that
до какого-то момента Я насколько знаю
there, in
что как бы там в
principle, too, like, with  the government was not
принципе тоже как бы с властью было не
very good, in my opinion, that's why they
очень хорошо они по-моему поэтому там
overthrew me, I'm not really in
что там свергли вот я не сильно как бы в
history, as it were, But
истории Как бы это Но
in principle, I think
а в принципе я думаю
that I don't even know, it's hard to say why, it's
что я даже не знаю сложно сказать почему
really hard there, too, as if there were constant
вот прям сложно там тоже постоян как бы
moments, as it were, for them here, as it were, because
были моменты у них тут как бы потому что
apparently, Well, apparently, your president didn't really
видимо Ну видимо ваш президент не сильно
want to, as it were, move away from what, as it were,
хотел как бы отойти от того что как бы у
we, as it were, support and he, as it
нас ну как бы поддерживает и он это как
were, goes along the same path, let's say,
бы идёт по по такому же пути то допустим
Take Korea, for example, Yes, it also sort of
Взять вот Корею Да она же тоже как бы
split up, that is, part of North
разделилась вот то есть часть Северной
Korea helped Russia, but the other part,
Кореи помогала России а вот второй части
naturally, didn't. They, too, as if one
естественно нет Вот они тоже как бы одна
part decided to go one way. Well,
часть решила по одному Ну пути пойти Да
like the Soviet Union was built, in essence, the
как Советский Союз построить по сути вот
second part, as it were, on a different path. Decided to
вторая как бы по-другому пути Решила
go, as it were, Each country
пойти это как бы Каждая страна Сама
decides for itself Which path to take, and what do you
решает По ком пути идти а как вы
think, were you in Europe?
считаете вот в Европе
No, and what do you think, where is the best
были Нет а как считаете где лучший
standard of living, in Russia or in
уровень жизни в России или в
Europe?
Европе
Well, as I would say, as it were, Well, it's
Ну как бы я так скажу как бы ну мне
hard for me to say because I've never been there
сложно говорить потому что я там не была
at all, I have friends who left
вообще вот у меня знакомые кто уехал
straight for permanent residence, no one came back, in
прямо на ПМЖ никто не вернулся вот в
general, Well, it depends on who you work there,
целом Ну смотря как бы кем там работать
probably, But
наверное Но
and I think that if it is possible I am
а я думаю что если как бы возможно
simply mistaken in this as far as I know
просто в этом ошибаюсь насколько я знаю
that, for example, in the same USA and
что как бы допустим в той же США
Germany they do not collect money for treatment by SMS, so
Германии на лечение СМСками деньги не
for me this is
собирают вот как бы это для меня это
just such a huge plus that
прям вот ну такой жильный плюс который
they cover up all the minuses that exist,
вот все минусы которые есть они вот
so to speak, completely and
прикрывают вот как бы от слово совсем и
so because it is
как бы ну потому что
difficult for me of course to find the words, but
бы сложно конечно подобрать слова но как
like this Just this one thing is such a big
бы вот Одно только это это такой жирный
plus that even if they tell me now
плюс что даже если там мне сейчас скажут
that they have it there, I don’t know, it’s cold there
что у них там там не знаю холодно там
or heating is expensive Well, ours is also
или отопление дорогое Ну у нас тоже
expensive But I would like it if it were like this for
дорогое Но вот как бы я бы хотела чтобы
us, well,
у нас было
like I am a patriot of my
так ну как бы я я прямо патриот своей
country I don’t want to go anywhere Well, maybe I ca
страны Я не хочу никуда уезжать Ну может
n’t because I don’t know the
и не могу потому что у меня нет знания
language there But I really want
там языка Вот Но я очень хочу чтобы у
us to have, for example, some Well, some
нас например было какие-то Ну какие-то
things were m that are there, I kind of miss this I would like it
вещи были м которые есть там вот мне как
if they told me, for example, that But
если бы мне сказали например что А вот
there, let’s say, a great person came and
там допустим мы пришёл человек класе и
said Well, I promise you I will make it so
сказал Вот я вам обещаю сделать так
that you, for example, don’t have
чтобы у вас там например не было а там
such a thing there, and there, for example, the price of life there,
такого что вот цена там жизни там
let’s say, for a child there  some kind of yes
допустим там вот ребёнка там какая-то да
if they didn't have time to collect it then it's like well there's
если вот не успели собрать то это как бы
no child that is I guarantee that
ну нет ребёнка то есть вот я гарантирую
EMS doesn't collect it for us anymore that's why
что вот нас ЭМС им больше не собирает
we each child if there is
вот намы каждого ребёнка если есть
treatment it will be like
лечение существует вообще оно будет как
damn I'll say Yes everything is like Okay then it does
бы блин я скажу Да всё как бы О'кей там
n't matter What do you want like that's right that's why
дальше Неважно Что ты хочешь как бы это
and if like there
поэтому и вот если как бы там
really is like that like well I'm not going to
действительно так как бы ну не собираюсь
as far as I know that it is like that then it's like
насколько я знаю что вс-таки так то как
their standard of living is better Although Because there
бы уровень жизни у них лучше Хотя Потому
is a guarantee that you give birth to a
что есть гарантия того что ты рожаешь
child he will live with you like
ребёнка он у тебя будет жить как бы
right somehow it will be because
верно как-то оно будет потому
anyway like that's the most important thing -
что всё равно как бы это самое главное -
it's still life no matter how you
это всё равно жизнь как не
twist the law
крути закон
g Luch standard of living in Europe or in
г Луч уровень жизни в Европе или в
Russia you told some long text
России вы какой-то длинный текст
then Where is it better to live Well I'm saying
рассказали то Где лучше жить Ну я говорю
that in Europe there is such a plus that in
что в Европе есть такой плюс который в
principle covers any minuses that's why I
принципе прикрывает любые минусы поэтому
understood everything better there And then I got lost in
там лучше понял всё А то я потерялся в
your words I knocked me out a little didn't
ваших словах Я вырубило меня немножко не
sleep today and what are the
спал сегодня а
minuses in
это какие минусы в
Europe in order to directly specifically
Европе для того чтобы пря конкретно
know the minus you need to live there ska
знать минус нужно пря там жить ска
covers the minuses Oso What are the minuses
перекрывает минусы Осо Какие минусы есть
in
в
Europe I  say it covers any
Европе я гово это перекрывает любые
minuses almost any minuses so
минусы практически любые минусы поэтому
as if they are unlikely there as if there is well there is
как бы если они есть врядли там как бы
no point in talking about them
вот там ну нет смысла про них говорить
because everywhere there are minuses in
потому что Везде есть свои минусы в
any country there are minuses right in
любой стране есть свои минусы прямо в
any they have a problem there in my opinion
любой у них там есть проблема по-моему
in the USA As far as I know there are problems with migrants
вот в США По сколько знаю с мигрантами
now
сейчас
but in Russia No with migrants you
проблемы а в России Нет с мигрантами
see migrants it is not always bad
проб видишь мигранты это не всегда плохо
in fact they raise the economy
на самом деле они поднимают экономику
it is the labor force as if and so on but in
это рабочая сила как бы и так далее но у
our country it is probably poorly controlled
нас Это наверно плохо контролируется
perhaps as if well and as if also as if
возможно как бы ну и как бы тоже как бы
two sides of the coin in this so there is a
две стороны медали в этом поэтому есть
problem here there is we as if we are talking about the
тут проблема есть мы же как бы говорим о
minuses of the country it is as if well but
минусах страны это же как бы вот нуно
there is expensive real estate it is how
там ну недвижимость дорогая её как бы
not to buy it there That is you as if if you were
там не купить То есть ты как бы если там
born there let's say in principle probably there if you
родился допустим в принципе наверно там
went there there may be
бы если туда приехал там может быть
something about Gilles there you just don't know about him And what are these
что Жиль там про ты его просто не А что
pictures you have there
это у вас за картинки там
behind it is a closet Can
сзади это шкаф
you touch it with your finger I
такой А можете пальцем дотронуться Я
want to see what the sizes are in
хочу посмотреть размеры какие в
comparison with the
сравнении с
hand while she turned away I
рукой пока она отвернулась я
ran away sneeze
убежал чихо
In short that's it we ran away while she turned away
Короче всё мы убежали пока отвернулась
Hello Let's be normal  let's chat
Привет Давай по нормально пообщаемся Ты
Where are you from We are from Tyumen And where are you from I am from
откуда Мы из Тюмени А вы откуда Я из
Lithuania How do we have
Литвы ка у
Lithuania So what are you talking about here I am
Литва Так о чём здесь разговариваете
just chatting with Russians with Ukrainians
просто общаюсь с россиянами с украинцами
I understand you are you are in the entrance somewhere Not
Я так понимаю вы вы в подъезде где-то Не
this is your
это свой до
home
дом
our laundry Where can I smoke a hookah
наше прачечная Где можно покурить кальян
in the house I don't smoke a hookah it's cool What are you
в доме не курю кальян прикольно О чём
talking about here young Virgo listen I just
тут общаетесь юная Дева слушайте только
registered yesterday and today decided to
зарегистрировалась и сегодня решила
go out to
выйти в
your thing yeah And what are you doing there roulette TV
вашу штучку да А вы там что рулет ТВ
in our thing everything is very
ведёте в нашей штучке тут очень всё
interesting here Listen here is a little question How did the
интересно Слушайте а вот такой вопросик
war affect you somehow one
Да как вас там как-то война задела
of your friends is fighting I don't
кто-то из знакомых воюет я не не
talk I don't talk about it just about
разговариваю Я не о воне просто о
relatives Do you have any relatives I do
родственниках Есть ли родственники
n't talk about the war I understand
какие-то не разговариваю о войне понял
Listen how are you with prices now
Слушай а как у вас с ценами сейчас
everything is
всё насколько
fine well the dollar fell the
ну доллар упал всё отлично Вчера доллар
dollar fell the prices didn't
доллар упал цены же не
fall yesterday we bought a car from Belarus
упали машинку вчера купили с Беларуссии
everything is fine what kind of car
всё нормально какую машинку
yesterday
вчера
i5 from Belarus they produce X5 in Belarus
и5 из белорусси в Белоруссии выпускают
Yes we bought from  Belarus used
Да купили из Белоруссии бэушную
Yes used Yes of the twenty-second
Да бэушную Да двадцать второго
year I understood stolen in
года понял украденную в
Ukraine It doesn't matter stolen in
Украине Это уже неважно украденный в
Ukraine yeah Yeah Well maybe it
Украине да Угу Ну может быть те так
seems so And what do you
кажется А ты кем
do
работаешь
Lawyer what lawyers
Юрист что юристи
huh taxes and taxation Listen
тиш налоги и налогообложения Слушай
let me somehow normally so that I can
давай я как-то нормально чтобы я тебя
see you otherwise it turns out I see the wall as if I'm
видел а то получается я стену вижу будто
talking to the Wall Well you're playing roulette now I don't really want to Yeah I'm not playing
говорю Ну ты ведёшь сейчас рулетку не
roulette at all I
охота особо Да не веду я рулетку никакую
came to talk Well YouTube I'm not playing
я зашёл поговорить А ну YouTube Не веду
YouTube I just came to talk I
я YouTube я просто зашёл поговорить Я
watched Zelensky Trump's press conference
посмотрел пресс-конференцию Зеленского
and came to just talk with
трампа и зашёл себе просто поговорить с
Russians
россиянами
Ukrainians Come back to se now I'll
украинцами Возвращайся по се сейчас я
load the hookah and come Okay
кальян загружу и приду
what do you load the hookah with Darkside
О'кей чем загружаешь кальян дарксайдом
Damn I don't know all these topics Well why are you
Блин я не шарю всех этих темах Ну зачем
asking then Well like I'm cherry
спрашиваешь тогда Ну типа я там вишня
apple What are these flavors
яблоко Какие эти ароматы
Tokyo shot after all blueberry cranberry
Токийский шотт ведь черника клюква
marshmallow
маршмеллоу прикольно
cool Yeah And you here What are you talking about well
Угу А ты здесь О чём разговариваешь а ну
with  boys about war with girls about different things
с пацанами о войне с девчонками о разном
Load hookah
Загрузи кальян
please so So what What are we going to
пожалуйста так Ну и что О чём мы будем
talk about I listen about not
говорить я слушай о воне не
talking about that I'm not talking about that I want to
разговаривать я не о воне я о цена хочу
talk about the price how much do you have Well what are the prices
поговорить сколько у вас Ну какие цены
for what do you remember can you
на что помнишь можешь
tell me the prices Well what are you
сказать цены Ну что тебя
interested in I'm generally like look when I
интересует я вообще вот смотри когда я
go into some
захожу например в какой-то
store for example I just pay with a card and
магазин я просто расплачиваюсь картой и
leave I'm not interested in prices in principle
ухожу меня в принципе цены не интересуют
and the only thing I remember when I
а единственное что я помню когда я
bought I had
покупала был у
at first then I had a Mazda
сначала потом у меня был была Mazda
after me
после ме бы
x55 I had a
x55 у меня был
diesel I'm
дизельный Мне
35 when I had a diesel diesel I
35 когда у меня был дизель дизель я
filled up
заправляла
somewhere around 48 rubles probably it was 49
где-то ну рублей 48 наверное было 49
How much did I buy it in Belarus
Почем в Беларуси
I think it was a
купила Я думаю это
SES if you bought it Oh well Approximately
сес если ты покупал О ну Приблизительно
how much did it cost in
сколько это стоило в
Belarus I think it's
Беларуси Я думаю сейчас это
not important now yes yes it's quite cheaper than
неважно да да достаточно дешевле чем у
here to buy it despite the fact that its
нас здесь купить её при том что она
configuration was much higher than in
комплектации была ну гораздо выше чем в
Crimea I once
Крым когда-то
came to Crimea Well I basically live
приезжала в Крым Ну я в принципе живу
Tyumen Yekaterinburg Yalta Turkey
Тюмень Екатеринбург Ялта Турция
Kazakhstan
Казахстан
No I'm like that
Нет я так-то
married One does not
замужем Одно другому не
interfere with the other Well, maybe it does not interfere with you, that is
мешает Ну может тебе не мешает это уже
another question It does not interfere with me that you are
другой вопрос мне не мешает то что ты
anyway no why should I
равно нет я зачем
be if I have a higher education I am a
быть если у меня высшее образование Я
lawyer I told you earlier well that is what is
юрист Я же тебе раньше сказала ну это ж
called with a higher education
типа называется с высшим образованием
they are kind of more valued
они как бы больше котируются
Why should I be if my husband
Зачем мне быть если у меня муж хорошо
earns well And what about the lip who
зарабатывает А что с губой кто
[applause]
[аплодисменты]
cracked cracked Yes and that
треснул треснуло Да а этото
was so that the bunny and who does the husband
было так что зайка и кем муж
work as yes the husband works what
работает да муж работает какая тебе
difference does it make to you who he works as Well, like the sphere
разница кем он работает Ну типа сфера
Whatever who he works as he
Какая кем бы он не работал он отлично
earns well so that I have a
зарабатывает для того чтобы у меня был
personal driver or rather my son
личный водитель точнее у моего сына
whom he drives and to study in the second shift so that I
которого он отвозит а во вторую смену
go to what is this for what
учиться чтобы я ездила на что это за что
he could not go to a normal private school that he
он не мог в нормальную школу частную что
studied in the first shift I do not like the
в первую смену учился не Мне нравится во
second We have a private school anyway it is a
вторую У нас у нас и так частная школа
private fee-based school it is
это частная платная школа
comprehensive but it is private that is
она общеобразовательная но она частная
not ordinary And for which we
то есть не обычная А за которую мы
pay money per month in the second shift
платим в месяц денежку во вторую смену
Yeah damn perne and I know you can
Да блин перне а я тебе знаешь ты можешь
laugh I'm
поржать Я
laughing Come on come on now I'm already laughing Come on
ржу Давай ну-ка пор я уже ржу Давай
tell me tell me why the second shift
расскажи Расскажи почему во вторую смену
because our son is a hockey player and he is on the ice during the
потому что у нас сын хоккеист и он в
first shift
первую смену
and studies during the second shift I
на льду а во вторую смену учится Поня Я
understand that And in a private school everyone there is a
так понял И в частной школе там все
hockey player Yes because
хоккеисты Да потому что на вторую смену
everyone goes to the second shift or was the second shift made just for him
все ходят или только ради него сделали
No there is the first second shift
вторую смену Нет там первая вторая смена
in principle like
в принципе как
in all
во во всех
schools Listen I will tell you this in
школах Слушай я тебе вот се скажу в
private schools in private schools there are no second
частных школах в частных школах вторых
shifts because private schools Well
смен нету потому что частные школы Ну
call me if you want me to give you a
позвони я тебе хочешь я тебе дам номер
phone number Call But I am not
телефона Позвони Но мне как бы ты не
interested in you and I am not interested in you right away
интересен и твоя сразу не интересен
look I will tell you this now in short yes
смотри я тебе вот сейс скажу короче да
So call and find out Call and find out it is
Так позвони узнай Позвони узнай это
called the school Estet Center Call
называется школа Эстет центр Позвони
near the Kadelak Center you are located
около около каделак центра находишься
find out and call is it open now or
узнай и позвони она сейчас работает или
not and that's it Well of course time time is already
нет и всё Ну конечно время время-то уже
our center so time of night school
у нас центр так так время ночи школа
center first hour of the night so center in
центр первый ча ночи поэтому центр даком
what city in what city
городе в каком
And then I
городе А дальше я
will switch And then you
переключу А дальше ты
nothing look there e I am you here with Look you
ниче смотри там е я те вот с Смотри ты
are sitting in  shabby and not
сидишь в ободранной
really on the balcony you smoke and put on
н толком на балконе куришь да надеваешь
this fur coat in short because it's
на себя вот эту шубу короче потому что
cold there, there's no heating, the renovation is
там холодно не отапливается ремонт
unfinished, you can see it there, in short, damn, it's
недоделанный там видно ж короче блин
not even painted normally This is on
даже не покрашено нормально Вот это
the side Yes, my son goes to a private school for the
сбоку Да сын ходит в платную школу на
second shift because he's a hockey player, you
вторую смену потому что он хоккеист ты
just know, and I'll tell you this
просто знаешь и и я тебе вот что скажу
You look very cheap, like, well, good These are
Ты выглядишь очень дёшево как ну
yours Yes, these are mine because I'm a
хоро Это же твои Да это мои потому что я
man who can appreciate a normal
мужик который могу оценить нормальную
girl and some kind of you, in short, a
девушку и какую-то типа у тебя короче
manicure, a manicure, a cheap fur coat and just
маникюр маникюр дешёвая шуба да и просто
simply the most terrible makeup, just the
просто ужаснейший мейкап просто
most terrible And I don't have makeup, I won't
ужаснейший А у меня мейкапа нету я не
put it on, this is
накрашу это
real, listen, and these cords are hanging there
реально слушай и вот эти шнуры там висят
It's just like you know, like a rich person, this is how it is in the
Это просто как знаешь по богатому так в
house I'll tell you this Listen, I'm
доме я тебе вот что скажу Слушай я тебе
not going to If your husband Yes, had
же не собираюсь Если бы твой муж Да имел
at least a little money, at least a little Yes, I'm
хоть немножко денег хоть немножко Да я
not saying that he would have made it so that
не говорю что он сделал бы так чтобы
the child went to the first shift Yes, but he
ребёнок ходил на первую смену Да но он
would have invested a little in
бы как бы немножко инвестировал в
you, there is still something here  there are also tiles
тебя ещ тут вот есть ещё есть плитка
that I will lay Yes tomorrow myself
которую я буду ложить Да завтра сама Да
And you think I don't care at all Look Wait Listen
и ты думаешь мне вообще бераз
I don't understand But
смотри Подожди Слушай я не понимаю А
if your son has a personal
если вот у тебя у сына есть личный
driver Why aren't there these
водитель Да почему нету этих э
repairmen who will come and
ремонтников которые придут и за
literally do this repair in 3-4 days
буквально там 3-4 дня сделают этот
[laughter]
[смех]
like squeak
лайк писка
comment write on y instag I don't know
комент пись на й instag Я не знаю для
what this is for that is there to look at the office and
чего це то для то там дивитись на офес а
for you one two or three clicks and you
для тебе один два або три клика а ты
find me and I will click in me There are a lot of
тримае мене и я буду кти в мене там Купа
fouls and in me there will be a cool setting to
фолов и в мене буде класний настр щоб
do but cool video pp
робити но крут вдео ппи
find
найд
So come on
Так давай чка